import { Question } from "@/types/Question";

export const questionsByWeek: { [week: string]: Question[] } = {
  week1: [
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a consumptive value?",
      options: ["timber", "firewood", "non-timber forest products", "education"],
      answer: "education",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a forest type found in India?",
      options: ["Mediterranean dry", "Tropical dry", "Montane temperate", "Alpine"],
      answer: "Mediterranean dry",
    },
    {
      question:
        "“Plant community, predominantly comprised of trees and other woody vegetation, usually with a closed canopy\" is",
      options: [
        "silvicultural definition of forests", "FAO definition of forests", "legal definition of forests", "ecological definition of forests",
      ],
      answer: "ecological definition of forests",
    },
    {
      question: "According to the Supreme Court, the word forest must be understood according to its",
      options: [
        "biological meaning",
        "ecological meaning",
        "silvicultural meaning",
        "dictionary meaning",
      ],
      answer: "dictionary meaning",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a use value?",
      options: ["direct value", "indirect value", "option value", "existence value"],
      answer: "existence value",
    },
    {
      question: "According to the Supreme Court, the term forest land includes",
      options: [
        "some area recorded as forest in the Government record according to ownership",
        "any area recorded as forest in the Government record according to ownership",
        "some area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
        "any area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
      ],
      answer: "any area recorded as forest in the Government record irrespective of ownership",
    },
    {
      question: "Tropical moist forests do not include",
      options: ["broadleaved forests", "wet evergreen forests", "semi-evergreen forests", "moist deciduous forests"],
      answer: "broadleaved forests",
    },
    {
      question: "The value of leaving use and non-use values for offspring’s or future generations is called",
      options: ["altruistic value", "bequest value", "existence value", "option value"],
      answer: "bequest value",
    },
    {
      question: "The term 'forest' originates from",
      options: [
        "Latin foris meaning outside",
        "Greek foris meaning outside",
        "Latin foris meaning trees",
        "Greek foris meaning trees",
      ],
      answer: "Latin foris meaning outside",
    },
    {
      question: "The value derived from the knowledge of use of resources by others in the current generation is called",
      options: ["altruistic value", "bequest value", "existence value", "option value"],
      answer: "altruistic value",
    },
  ],
  week2: [
    {
      question: "Lithosere is an example of",
      options: ["hydrosere", "xerosere", "psammosere", "halosere"],
      answer: "xerosere",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these depicts correctly the lithosere primary succession?",
      options: [
        "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Rock → Foliose lichen → Crustose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Moss → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Rock → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
        "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Shrub → Herbaceous stage → Moss → Woodland → Climax",
      ],
      answer: "Rock → Crustose lichen → Foliose lichen → Moss → Herbaceous stage → Shrub → Woodland → Climax",
    },
    {
      question: "At compensation point,",
      options: [
        "photosynthesis = respiration",
        "photosynthesis > respiration",
        "photosynthesis < respiration",
        "none of these",
      ],
      answer: "photosynthesis = respiration",
    },
    {
      question:
        "The study of life history / general features of forest crops with respect to environmental factors is called",
      options: ["foresticulture", "monoculture", "silviculture", "silvics"],
      answer: "silvics",
    },
    {
      question: "A climax caused by wildfires is an example of",
      options: ["climatic climax", "edaphic climax", "disclimax", "catastrophic climax"],
      answer: "catastrophic climax",
    },
    {
      question: "Net primary productivity is given by",
      options: ["APAR + LUE", "APAR X LUE", "APAR - LUE", "APAR ÷ LUE"],
      answer: "APAR X LUE",
    },
    {
      question:
        "Practical application of scientific, technical and economic principles of forestry comes under which branch of forestry?",
      options: ["forest management", "forest economics", "forest mensuration", "forest protection"],
      answer: "forest management",
    },
    {
      question: "In the context of plant nutrition, boron is",
      options: ["macronutrient", "micronutrient", "primary nutrient", "secondary nutrient"],
      answer: "micronutrient",
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is not a characteristic of pioneer species",
      options: [
        "ability to grow on bare rocks",
        "ability to tolerate extreme temperatures",
        "large size",
        "short life span",
      ],
      answer: "large size",
    },
    {
      question: "The climax near Tindni village is being controlled by disturbance by cattle. This is an example of",
      options: ["climatic climax", "edaphic climax", "disclimax", "catastrophic climax"],
      answer: "disclimax",
    },
  ],
  week3: [
    {
      question: "Mechanical action of ocean waves is an example of",
      options: ["chemical weathering", "physical weathering", "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "physical weathering",
    },
    {
      question: "Khadar is a type of",
      options: ["black cotton soil", "alluvial soil", "saline soil", "red and yellow soil"],
      answer: "alluvial soil",
    },
    {
      question: "In soil profile, C refers to",
      options: ["organic surface layer", "topsoil layer", "subsoil layer", "substratum layer"],
      answer: "substratum layer",
    },
    {
      question: "Regur is a term for",
      options: ["black cotton soil", "alluvial soil", "saline soil", "red and yellow soil"],
      answer: "black cotton soil",
    },
    {
      question: "Bangar is a type of",
      options: ["black cotton soil", "alluvial soil", "saline soil", "red and yellow soil"],
      answer: "alluvial soil",
    },
    {
      question: "Soil formation is dependent upon",
      options: ["vegetation", "time", "climate", "all of the above"],
      answer: "all of the above",
    },
    {
      question: "Thermal stresses lead to",
      options: ["chemical weathering", "physical weathering", "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "physical weathering",
    },
    {
      question: "Carbonation is an example of",
      options: ["chemical weathering", "physical weathering", "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "chemical weathering",
    },
    {
      question: "Cryofracturing is an example of",
      options: ["chemical weathering", "physical weathering", "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "physical weathering",
    },
    {
      question: "Hydrolysis is an example of",
      options: ["chemical weathering", "physical weathering", "biological weathering", "none of the above"],
      answer: "chemical weathering",
    },
  ],
  week4: [
    {
      question: "For absolute form factor, the reference for the base of the cylinder is",
      options: [
        "base of the tree",
        "breast height",
        "10% of tree height",
        "20% of tree height"
      ],
      answer: "base of the tree"
    },
    {
      question: "For normal form factor, the reference for the base of the cylinder is",
      options: [
        "base of the tree",
        "breast height",
        "10% of tree height",
        "20% of tree height"
      ],
      answer: "10% of tree height"
    },
    {
      question: "In India, the breast height is considered to be",
      options: ["1.37 m", "1.47 m", "1.57 m", "2.47 m"],
      answer: "1.37 m"
    },
    {
      question: "Measurement of height based on similar triangles comes under:",
      options: ["similar measurement", "dissimilar measurement", "direct measurement", "indirect measurement"],
      answer: "indirect measurement"
    },
    {
      question: "For a tree with dbh = 45.6 cm, height = 27 m and total stem volume of 1.78 cum, the artificial form factor for the tree is:",
      options: ["0.1", "0.2", "0.3", "0.4"],
      answer: "0.4"
    },
    {
      question: "Consider a stand of eucalyptus trees that are on average 30 cm in diameter and spaced on a regular 3 m grid. Find the spacing factor.",
      options: ["5", "10", "15", "data insufficient"],
      answer: "10"
    },
    {
      question: "Diameter over bark (dob), diameter under bark (dub) and bark thickness (tb) are related as:",
      options: [
        "dob = dub + tb",
        "dob = dub - tb",
        "dob = dub + 2 × tb",
        "dob = dub - 2 × tb"
      ],
      answer: "dob = dub + 2 × tb"
    },
    {
      question: "For false form factor, the reference for the base of the cylinder is",
      options: ["base of the tree", "breast height", "10% of tree height", "20% of tree height"],
      answer: "breast height"
    },
    {
      question: "Choose the correct statement:",
      options: [
        "For a non-circular cross-section, girth tape over-estimates the sectional area.",
        "For a non-circular cross-section, girth tape under-estimates the sectional area.",
        "For a non-circular cross-section, girth tape correctly estimates the sectional area.",
        "None of these is a correct statement."
      ],
      answer: "For a non-circular cross-section, girth tape over-estimates the sectional area."
    },
    {
      question: "A tree has dbh of 25 cm. Find its basal area in sq m.",
      options: [".049", ".096", ".149", ".195"],
      answer: ".049"
    }
  ],
  week5: [
    {
      question: "“This sampling employs a simple rule of selecting every kth unit starting with a number chosen at random from 1 to k as the random start.” We're talking about",
      options: ["Simple random sampling", "Systematic sampling", "Stratified sampling", "Multistage sampling"],
      answer: "Systematic sampling"
    },
    {
      question: "IMU stands for",
      options: ["Imperial metering unit", "Inertial metering unit", "Imperial measurement unit", "Inertial measurement unit"],
      answer: "Inertial measurement unit"
    },
    {
      question: "___ is how close the measured values are to the correct value.",
      options: ["Accuracy", "Precision", "Bias", "Variance"],
      answer: "Accuracy"
    },
    {
      question: "A list of sampling units is called a",
      options: ["frame", "window", "sample", "population"],
      answer: "frame"
    },
    {
      question: "The time of flight for LiDAR is 0.00001 sec. Find the distance of the object from the instrument.",
      options: ["500 m", "1000 m", "1500 m", "2000 m"],
      answer: "1500 m"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of these is correct?",
      options: [
        "Plane surveying takes into account the true shape of the Earth and is used for smaller areas (< 250 sq km)",
        "Plane surveying takes into account the true shape of the Earth and is used for larger areas (> 250 sq km)",
        "Geodetic surveying takes into account the true shape of the Earth and is used for smaller areas (< 250 sq km)",
        "Geodetic surveying takes into account the true shape of the Earth and is used for larger areas (> 250 sq km)"
      ],
      answer: "Geodetic surveying takes into account the true shape of the Earth and is used for larger areas (> 250 sq km)"
    },
    {
      question: "A sampling procedure such that each possible combination of sampling units out of the population has the same chance of being selected is referred to as",
      options: ["Simple random sampling", "Systematic sampling", "Stratified sampling", "Multistage sampling"],
      answer: "Simple random sampling"
    },
    {
      question: "The frequency of flyovers is an indicator of",
      options: ["spatial resolution", "temporal resolution", "spectral resolution", "radiometric resolution"],
      answer: "temporal resolution"
    },
    {
      question: "___ is how close the measured values are to each other.",
      options: ["Accuracy", "Precision", "Bias", "Variance"],
      answer: "Precision"
    },
    {
      question: "Bathymetric LiDAR uses",
      options: ["far infrared light", "near infrared light", "orange light", "green light"],
      answer: "green light"
    }
  ],
};